Mikael Röthig

Skilled software developer with a passion for crafting user-friendly experiences. I excel in front-end development, bringing clean code and visually appealing designs to life, ensuring a seamless and engaging user journey across all devices.

mrrothig@gmail.com +31 (0) 62 089 8563 Enschede, Netherlands github.com/mikaelrothig linkedin.com/in/mikaelrothig

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Junior Web Developer · Positive Digits Apr 2023 - Sep 2024

- Designed and executed a multi-language, multi domain lead generation site as part of a two person team using Sulu, Tailwind CSS, and Stimulus JS.
- Contributed to the ongoing maintenance of a web shop with 100,000 products, working alongside a mentor to keep product information accurate and the site running efficiently.
- Created clean and efficient front-end designs for clients and in house websites.

IT Specialist · Cape Town Engineering Jan 2017 - Mar 2020

 Managed setup and maintenance of hardware and software in the company office during my studies.

EDUCATION

BCIS in Game Design & Development

Vega School Cape Town Jan 2017- Dec 2019

- Learned to develop games using the Unity engine and C#.
- Designed and modeled 3D game assets using Blender.
- Represented Vega at the Cape Town Electronic Games Exhibition in 2017 and 2018.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, PHP, C#

Libraries & Frameworks

Symfony, Shopware, Sulu, Hugo, Astro, Tailwind CSS, Stimulus JS

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Unity, Blender

LANGUAGES

English (Native), Dutch (Elementary), German (Elementary)

INTERESTS

Football, watersports specifically kitesurfing, traveling, meeting new people, working in a team